# Hyeonmin Lee

# Postdoctoral Researcher at Seoul National University

I'm a postdoctoral researcher at Seoul National University, working with Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon. I received my Ph.D. and B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering from Seoul National University, supervised by Prof. Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon (Seoul National University) and Prof. Taejoong "Tijay" Chung (Virginia Tech). My research interests lie in network security and its measurement: Are we using the network correctly and securely? How can we make the network (more) secure?

# **CONTACT INFORMATION**

EMAIL: min0921110@gmail.com

ADDRESS: Network Convergence and Security Lab, 5F, Building 301, 1, Gwanak-ro,

Gwanak-gu, Seoul, South Korea (08826)

HOMEPAGE: https://hyeonmin-lee.github.io/

### RESEARCH INTERESTS

NETWORK SECURITY — (especially) DNS security, Mail security SECURITY MEASUREMENT

# **POSITIONS**

APR 2022 - Present Postdoctoral Researcher, Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

• Supervisor: Prof. Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon

# **EDUCATION**

MAR 2016 - FEB 2022

**Ph.D.**, Computer Science and Engineering, Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

- Dissertation: "Understanding the DANE Ecosystem in Email: How Is It Deployed and Managed?"
- Laboratory: Network Convergence and Security Lab.
- Supervisors: Prof. Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon and Prof. Taejoong (Tijay) Chung

MAR 2011 - FEB 2016

**B.S.**, Computer Science and Engineering, Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

FALL 2014

Visiting Student, Information Technology, Uppsala University, Uppsala, Sweden

### **PUBLICATIONS**

### [c3] Under the Hood of DANE Mismanagement in SMTP

**Hyeonmin Lee**, Md. Ishtiaq Ashiq, Moritz Müller, Roland van Rijswijk-Deij, Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon, Taejoong Chung

In Proceedings of the 31st USENIX Security Symposium (Security'22), Boston, United States, Aug 2022

- Dataset [https://dane-study.github.io]

### [c2] A Longitudinal and Comprehensive Study of the DANE Ecosystem in Email

**Hyeonmin Lee**, Aniketh Gireesh, Roland van Rijswijk-Deij, Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon, Taejoong Chung

In Proceedings of the 29th USENIX Security Symposium (Security'20), Boston, United States, Aug 2020

- Dataset [https://dane-study.github.io]

# [c1] Development of Cellular Core Network Enabling Network Function Virtualization Hyeonmin Lee, Junghwan Song

The 28th Joint Conference on Communication and Information (JCCl'18), Yeosu, Korea, May 2018

# [j1] TwinPeaks: An Approach for Certificateless Public Key Distribution for the Internet and Internet of Things

Eunsang Cho, Jeongnyeo Kim, Minkyung Park, **Hyeonmin Lee**, Chorom Hamm, Soobin Park, Sungmin Sohn, Minhyeok Kang, Ted "Taekyoung" Kwon Elsevier Computer Networks (SCI-E)

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Mar 2016

#### Research Assistant

- FEB 2022

Network Convergence and Security Lab., Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

[Research Topic]

- Measuring how DANE is deployed in the SMTP ecosystem (Related achievement - Publication [c2])
- Investigating the underlying reasons for the DANE mismanagement (Related achievement Publication [c3])

MAY 2019

### Visiting Researcher

- AUG 2019

The Center for Cybersecurity, Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, USA

[Research Topic]

 Measuring and analyzing the ecosystem of DANE protocol in Email (Related achievement - Publication [c2]

**SPRING 2016** 

#### **Teaching Assistant**

Dept. of Computer Science and Engineering, Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea

• Engineering Frontiers and Leadership 2 Class

# RESEARCH PROJECT EXPERIENCES

Apr 2020

- DEC 2021

#### Research on Traceability for Data Stability on Cloud-edge Lifecycle

- Supported by Institute for Information and Communication Technology Promotion (IITP)
- Role: Researcher / Programmer

MAR 2021 - Nov 2021

21 /

# Abnormal Detection and Forensic Techniques using IoT Network Traffic Analysis

- Supported by Korea Institute of Information Security & Cryptology (KIISC)
- Role: Project Manager (Lab.) / Researcher / Programmer

APR 2016

- DEC 2020

### Versatile Network System Architecture for Multi-dimensional Diversity

 Supported by Institute for Information and Communication Technology Promotion (IITP) • Role: Project Manager (Lab.) / System Designer / Programmer

# AUG 2016

### Research and Development of Open 5G Reference Model

- FEB 2019
- Supported by Giga KOREA Foundation • Role: System Designer / Programmer
- **JUL 2015** - DEC 2015

# Development of Network Security Acceleration for Next-generation Lowpower SoC

- Supported by Samsung Electronics
- Role: Programmer

### PATENTS

- Network System and Method for Performing Message Security Thereof Ted "Taekyoung" Kwon, Hyunwoo Lee, Myungchul Kwak, Hyeonmin Lee, Junghwan Lim, Yoojung Shin
  - Registration No. 1022656110000
  - South Korea, Jun. 10, 2021
- Communication Method Based on Integrated Flat ID and System Ted "Taekyoung" Kwon, Hyunwoo Lee, Myungchul Kwak, Hyeonmin Lee, Dongjun Lee, Hyunchul Oh
  - Registration No. 1020231150000
  - South Korea, Sep. 11, 2019

# AWARDS & FELLOWSHIPS

- Aug 2018, Seoul National University Alumni Association Scholarship
- Fall 2014, Exchange Student Program to Uppsala University (Information Technology)

### TALKS & PRESENTATIONS

- · Aug 2020, USENIX Security, Online, "A Longitudinal and Comprehensive Study of the DANE Ecosystem in Email"
  - Slides [link]. Video [link]

### **MISCELLANEOUS**

#### MAR 2019 - FEB 2022

# **Expert Research Personnel** (military service)

Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

The expert research personnel system is a form of alternative military service in South Korea, where the military service is fulfilled by conducting research at a domestic university or company for three years. I had not been involved in any military research project throughout the service.

# REFERENCES

# Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon (tkkwon@snu.ac.kr)

 Professor, Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

### Taejoong (Tijay) Chung (tijay@vt.edu)

· Assistant Professor, Department of Computer Science, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, VA, **United States**